Edison Tang Lim

edisontanglim@yahoo.com | +1-408-797-8162

SUMMARY

<u>Deep experience across IT functions</u>, including 3 years in strategy and innovation; 6 years in architecture, standards, and product management; 1 year in methodology; 7 years in project management, system implementation, and consulting in 10 SAP projects; led global teams of up to 60 team members. Extensive knowledge in supply chain architecture and solutions. Solid hands-on software development background.

<u>Excellent track record in diverse IT initiative types</u>, including business transformation, supply chain architecture, merger and acquisition, SAP and non-SAP system integration, mega project implementation, legacy system elimination, Lean Six Sigma quality improvement, and organization capability building.

<u>Strong team leader</u> who knows how to lead and help teams to success. Consistent top-rated performer.

<u>Recognized innovator and expert</u>: speaker in international and regional conferences such as HP TechCon Global, HP SAP TechCon, SAP TechEd and d-code, and ASUG conferences.

<u>Global perspective</u>: grew up in Taiwan and the Philippines; international work experience in the United States, the Philippines, Canada, and Germany; multilingual, speaks fluent English, Mandarin Chinese, and Tagalog (Philippine national language); can converse in Cantonese and Fukienese Chinese dialects.

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Job functions: IT strategy and governance, architecture, product management, methodology and standards, project management, consulting, system implementation

SAP: SAP Order-to-Cash, Materials Management, Fiori, Workflow, BRFplus, Personas, ALE, Solution Manager, HANA Cloud Platform, ECATT, ABAP

Integration architecture: ORTEC Load Building, JDA TMS, RedPrairie (JDA) WMS, Terra Forecasting, Accenture CAS, SAP-to-SAP global supply chain integration

Other: Supply chain, Consumer Packaged Goods (CPG), design thinking, Java, JavaScript, HTML5, SAPUI5, R, Android programming, design pattern

Certifications: Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, SAP Certified Application Associate - Order Fulfillment with SAP ERP 6.0 EHP5, ITIL V3 Foundation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hewlett-Packard Company – Cincinnati, OH, USA; Toronto, ON, Canada

January 2004 – Present

Innovation and Quality Manager for Procter & Gamble

January 2011 – Present

Responsibilities: Develop business case, strategy, and roadmap for innovation and quality initiatives; drive initiatives from idea to reality

- Delivered more than 20 initiatives; initiated SAP New Idea Team
- Generated \$1.5 million in savings through Lean Six Sigma improvements
- Set up the Solution Quality Network that connected governance, operation, and development organizations. The network identified and drove resolution to 700+ defects in the first 6 months
- Authored company-wide solution quality policies used across IT service vendors

SAP Order Management Application Manager / Architect for P&G

July 2009 - Present

Responsibilities: Member of Global Supply Chain Template Design Council; govern supply chain integration and solution vision, architecture, and standards; maintain continuity of supply chain expertise;

- Designed, governed, and directed solution architecture and development across more than 50 global and regional SAP implementation projects, including P&G's largest supply chain transformation
- Oversaw production solution health and problem management; reduced problem records by 20%
- Led SAP development transformation from procedural ABAP to object-oriented ABAP
- Mentored employees; trained more than 150 consultants

Project Manager / Methodology Champion for P&G

January 2007 – January 2010

Responsibilities: Lead SAP implementation projects; roll-out project implementation methodology to all project teams

- Led teams of up to 60 direct global team members through 3 full SAP project implementations; piloted automated testing that reduced testing time by 60%
- Delivered supply chain template solution for global reapplication
- Led HP technical training initiative; trained more than 200 technology consultants
- Rolled out new SAP project implementation methodology more than 250 project persons

SAP Integration Architect / Technical Project Manager for P&G

October 2005 – March 2007

Responsibilities: Align supply chain integration needs, priorities, and implementation approach with global business and IT leaders; architect P&G-Gillette global supply chain integration solution; lead technical project implementation

- Designed huge supply chain integration architecture that supported over \$1 billion in synergy savings
- Aligned business and IT integration approach to manageable scope and timeline
- Led global technical team of more than 40 members in delivering the Gillette integration solution; the solution became P&G's global standard for integrating internal and external supply chain systems

SAP Sales and Distribution Implementation Lead for P&G

January 2004 – December 2005

Responsibilities: Lead implementation teams through 2 full SAP implementation projects

- Automated P&G North America's high volume, high velocity order management processes; the solution became P&G's globally most important sales and distribution productivity solution
- Replaced legacy shipping and transportation solution used in more than 50 North America plants

Procter & Gamble Company – Philippines; Germany; USA

June 2002 - December 2003

SAP Sales and Distribution Systems Analyst

June 2002 – December 2003

Responsibilities: Analyze sales and distribution processes; design, configure, and develop sales and distribution solutions; participate in SAP technology implementation projects

• Supported 4 SAP implementation projects; trained approximately 60 users and team members

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley, Haas School of Business – Berkeley, USA

August 2015 - Current

Master of Business Administration (MBA), EWMBA Program – Class of 2018

De La Salle University – Manila, Philippines

June 1998 – August 2002

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Major in Software Technology

- Summa Cum Laude
- Vice President of Academic Affairs, La Salle Computer Society

Technology and Business Massive Open Online Courses – Online

2013 - 2015